<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wwi-red-cross</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1914-08-31/ed-1/seq-1/#words=CROSS+Cross+Red+RED</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      U. S. RED CROSS
      HIRES OCEAN LINER
      WOUNDED
      Hamburg-American Steamer Hamburg, as American Hos
      pital Ship, Sails Saturday.

      TAKES 200 DOCTORS.
      Warring Governments Will
      Recognize Neutrality of Ves
      sel Manned by Americans.

      WASHINGTON, Aug. 31 (Asso
      ciated Press). The American Red
      Cross announced to-day that it had
      chartered the steamer Hamburg of
      the Hamburg American line, which
      will be renamed Red Cross and sail on
      Saturday for Europe.
      ...
      Miss Mabel T. Boardman, chairman
      of the National Relief Board of the
      American Red Cross, will go to New
      York to-night to take personal charge
      of the final preparations for the de
      parture of the ship.
      The Hamburg ... will be
      painted white, with a red "hospital
      band" around the upper part of her
      hull ...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1914-12-10/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      ONLY SOLDIERS WILL RECEIVE RED CROSS AID
      Helping of Europe's Hungry People Given Up for Field Service.
      SECRETARY GARRISON.
      Annual Report Calls for 25,000 More Regulars, Additional Officers to Train Recruits, 
      and Immediate Legislation Providing Trained Reserves...

      To better shoulder the titanic task of ministering to the tens of thousands of 
      wounded and dying soldiers in the battling armies of Europe, the American National 
      Red Cross, at its tenth annual meeting at the Shoreham yesterday, dropped the 
      staggering burden of feeding, clothing and otherwise aiding the suffering and starving 
      noncombatants of Europe.

      The Red Cross was forced to take action unprecedented in its long annals of 
      humanitarianism. This was done upon the motion of Vice President Robert W. de 
      Forest, of New York...

      President Woodrow Wilson, president of the Red Cross, presided but a few minutes, 
      but while he held the gavel he made an address which clearly expressed his deep 
      interest in the Red Cross...

      Miss Mabel T. Boardman, chairman of the National Relief Board, in speaking on 
      "The Red Cross and the European War," expressed "deep grief" that the Red Cross 
      should be forced to relinquish its efforts for the alleviation of suffering among the 
      noncombatants...

      Miss Jane A. Delano, vice chairman of the nursing service... explained that during 
      the last month hundreds of nurses have volunteered aid and hundreds of men 
      have offered to serve as orderlies and stretcher bearers. "The nurses and surgeons 
      now in Europe," said Miss Delano, "represent eleven states and twenty-four cities."
      ...

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1917-12-12/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93060090/1917-12-13/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      The First Stnti-Annual Report Of the War Council of
      The American RED CROSS,

      Washington, D. C. Dee. 2 ..The American! people are to
      On behalf of the WarCouncil.y the richest! people in the
      world the richest in resources richest in obligations and in op-
      portunities. The Red Cross aims to mobilize the hearts and souls
      of America toward binding up the wounds of a bleeding world.

      ......

      MONEYS APPROPRIATED
      Following the preliminary report recently made on the
      work in Europe of the American Red Cross the WarCouncil
      presents herewith a summary of the work of the Red Cross,
      both in the United States and in Europe from May 10,
      1917, to November 1, 1917.
      During this period the War Council appropriated from
      the War Fund (including 7,659,000 advanced to chapters
      for purchase of material and to be returned to the War
      Fund)...

      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84031081/1917-12-24/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      ARE YOU KNITTING YOUR ...
      The Moving Picture People Find Time between Scenes to Help 
      Red Cross in Its Big Winter Drive.

      Florence Nightingale Not Founder, as Commonly Supposed; 
      Organization Due to Efforts of Clara Barton

      Ask who founded the Red Cross and nine persons out of ten will reply 
      confidently "Florence Nightingale." ... The inspiration of a noble 
      American woman completed the work of the Red Cross society ... 
      This was Clara Barton, born the year after Miss Nightingale ...
      Today the necessity for universal skill [in knitting] is greater than in 
      those other days ... millions of boys in khaki and blue are clamoring 
      for the warm, worsted garments which the Red Cross is collecting ...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-02-24/ed-1/seq-53/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Keeping Pershing's Army in Good Spirits
      Henry P. Davison, Chairman of the Red Cross War Council, 
      Explains the Way Our Soldiers Are Informed Truthfully 
      of Home Conditions

      If a cross section photograph could be taken to-day of 
      the activities of the American Red Cross, both at home 
      and abroad, the resultant picture would be a great 
      comfort to every woman who has a husband or brother, 
      father or son, enlisted in America’s fighting forces. 
      For it would show a scope of endeavor far greater than 
      the original function of the Red Cross, which was merely 
      to care for the wounded. The wounded still get attention, 
      all that the best doctors and nurses can give them; but 
      that is only one phase of the work that the American Red 
      Cross now symbolizes. The rest of the picture is new.
      ...
      “In this new picture, which has been enlarged to meet 
      the demands of modern warfare, the flag of the American 
      Red Cross flies over every camp and cantonment where 
      American men are being trained for battle, symbolizing 
      a protection to their morale as well as their creature 
      comforts. 
      ...
      ‘Moreover, every parcel [to POWs] is personally 
      receipted for by the prisoner, and the postcard receipt 
      sent back to the Red Cross ... The Red Cross has 
      already begun to send food and clothing to him and 
      that this service will be maintained as long as he remains 
      a prisoner of war.’
      ...
      ‘This is the message which the American Red Cross 
      has carried to Europe and which it will continue to 
      deliver there so long as there are hungry Allies to 
      be fed, homeless ones to be housed and broken 
      lives to be rebuilt.’
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064293/1918-05-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "A great net of mercy drawn through an ocean of unspeakable pain"
      How Was the Last War Fund Spent?

      It is a fair question—and it is fairly answered in the
      detailed and itemized reports that have been published
      in the newspapers of every town and city of the land.
      You never saw it? Then ask at the nearest Red
      Cross Chapter, or write, for the Red Cross wants you
      to know where your money went.

      They say that Red Cross supplies have a way of
      coming through on time.
      Italy surely has found us not wanting in prompt
      ness when her great trial came.
      And Roumania—they said no allied nation could
      get through to help her dire need.
      But the Red Cross found a way.

      It’s not always a cheap way—“Needs must”
      costs money. But did you give that money to be
      saved—or to save lives? ...
      And of one thing you may be sure. Not one
      penny of that Hundred Million has gone for anything
      but War Relief.

      Your Red Cross needs another hundred million to
      lighten just a little of the awful load of misery “over
      there.” Your share is all that you can give—and
      then a little more.
      Will you hold up your end?
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015387/1918-05-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      THE BIG DRIVE FOR RED CROSS COMMENCES MONDAY
      Committees Appointed and Allotments Made In Various Wards.
      COVINGTON PARADE SATURDAY EVENING
      St. Tammany Parish Is Expected To Again Go Over The Top.

      Parish Chairman Poitevent has appointed chairmen in the different wards 
      to take charge of the Second Red Cross Drive, which starts Monday, May 20, 
      and these chairmen have appointed their local committeemen. The allotments 
      have been made for the different wards, and the total parish allotment of 
      $15,000 has been as equitably distributed as possible...

      Covington—E. G. Davis, E. J. Domergue, S. C. Bull, H. A. Mackie, ...
      John L. Haller, ward chairman, Third Ward, ...
      Each ward will provide for its own demonstrations and parades. 
      The Covington parade will take place at 5 o'clock to-day and will be 
      participated in by the Red Cross, the schools and St. Paul's College and 
      St. Scholastica's Academy...

      Capt. Herbert Smith, who spent nine months in the trenches at the front 
      ... spoke for the Red Cross at Slidell and Abita Springs, and Wednesday at 
      Covington. He related experiences of war conditions and the vital aid the 
      Red Cross provides to soldiers in the trenches...

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87065462/1918-12-12/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "NEW Red Cross Call" 
      "Roll of Member"

      Every Patriotic Citizen Urged to Help in Solution
      of Problems of Peace by Joining; America's Greatest Institution.

      WASHINGTON, D. C. Henry P. Davison, Chairman of the 
      War Council of the Red Cross, has issued to the 3,884 
      chapters and 22,000,000 members of the American Red Cross
      the following statement outlining the future policy of the American
      Red Cross:

      "The Roll Call of the nation is thus to be called at Christmas 
      time, that through enrollment in their Red Cross the American
      people may send a message to our soldiers still overseas and to 
      the peoples of the world that we are not merely content with 
      seeing our privates united with our allies in victory, but that our 
      abiding purpose is that the love, the sympathy and the intelligence 
      of all America shall be re-dedicated to the permanent service of
      mankind."
      —H. P. DAVISON

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88056166/1918-05-10/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "A Great Net of Mercy drawn through an Ocean of Unspeakable Pain"
      —American Red Cross

      The Call From No Man's Land

      The Spending of Your Hundred Million Dollars
      Busiest Budget in All the World Is a Red Cross War Fund
      —Every Dollar Spent Alleviates Misery.

      Last summer the public subscribed a hundred million dollars 
      to the Red Cross. ... It’s amazing that it [the Red Cross] has done 
      so much with so little money.

      ... The American Red Cross’ enormous job is to do whatever 
      it can to alleviate [suffering]—not after the war, not after governments 
      have deliberated and resolved; but right now, on the spot. ...

      [Article describes in detail how millions of dollars in Red Cross 
      funds were spent to assist refugees, to build hospitals, to provide 
      food, shelter, medical services and canteen services for soldiers 
      in France, Italy, and elsewhere, alleviating misery on an 
      unprecedented scale...]

      Every dollar it spends means misery alleviated. Its work 
      is building abroad for the United States the best good will in 
      this world. Whatever else the war may produce, we shall 
      be proud of our Red Cross.

      —From the Cottonwood chronicle (Idaho), May 10, 1918.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065528/1944-04-28/ed-1/?sp=2&q=world+war+i&r=-0.642,-0.015,2.284,1.409,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
