<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-wwi-red-cross</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1914-08-31/ed-1/seq-1/#words=CROSS+Cross+Red+RED</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      U. S. RED CROSS
      HIRES OCEAN LINER
      WOUNDED
      Hamburg-American Steamer Hamburg, as American Hos
      pital Ship, Sails Saturday.

      TAKES 200 DOCTORS.
      Warring Governments Will
      Recognize Neutrality of Ves
      sel Manned by Americans.

      WASHINGTON, Aug. 31 (Asso
      ciated Press). The American Red
      Cross announced to-day that it had
      chartered the steamer Hamburg of
      the Hamburg American line, which
      will be renamed Red Cross and sail on
      Saturday for Europe.
      ...
      Miss Mabel T. Boardman, chairman
      of the National Relief Board of the
      American Red Cross, will go to New
      York to-night to take personal charge
      of the final preparations for the de
      parture of the ship.
      The Hamburg ... will be
      painted white, with a red "hospital
      band" around the upper part of her
      hull ...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1914-12-10/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      ONLY SOLDIERS WILL RECEIVE RED CROSS AID
      Helping of Europe's Hungry People Given Up for Field Service.
      SECRETARY GARRISON.
      Annual Report Calls for 25,000 More Regulars, Additional Officers to Train Recruits, 
      and Immediate Legislation Providing Trained Reserves...

      To better shoulder the titanic task of ministering to the tens of thousands of 
      wounded and dying soldiers in the battling armies of Europe, the American National 
      Red Cross, at its tenth annual meeting at the Shoreham yesterday, dropped the 
      staggering burden of feeding, clothing and otherwise aiding the suffering and starving 
      noncombatants of Europe.

      The Red Cross was forced to take action unprecedented in its long annals of 
      humanitarianism. This was done upon the motion of Vice President Robert W. de 
      Forest, of New York...

      President Woodrow Wilson, president of the Red Cross, presided but a few minutes, 
      but while he held the gavel he made an address which clearly expressed his deep 
      interest in the Red Cross...

      Miss Mabel T. Boardman, chairman of the National Relief Board, in speaking on 
      "The Red Cross and the European War," expressed "deep grief" that the Red Cross 
      should be forced to relinquish its efforts for the alleviation of suffering among the 
      noncombatants...

      Miss Jane A. Delano, vice chairman of the nursing service... explained that during 
      the last month hundreds of nurses have volunteered aid and hundreds of men 
      have offered to serve as orderlies and stretcher bearers. "The nurses and surgeons 
      now in Europe," said Miss Delano, "represent eleven states and twenty-four cities."
      ...

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1917-12-12/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn93060090/1917-12-13/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      The First Stnti-Annual Report Of the War Council of
      The American RED CROSS,

      Washington, D. C. Dee. 2 ..The American! people are to
      On behalf of the WarCouncil.y the richest! people in the
      world the richest in resources richest in obligations and in op-
      portunities. The Red Cross aims to mobilize the hearts and souls
      of America toward binding up the wounds of a bleeding world.

      ......

      MONEYS APPROPRIATED
      Following the preliminary report recently made on the
      work in Europe of the American Red Cross the WarCouncil
      presents herewith a summary of the work of the Red Cross,
      both in the United States and in Europe from May 10,
      1917, to November 1, 1917.
      During this period the War Council appropriated from
      the War Fund (including 7,659,000 advanced to chapters
      for purchase of material and to be returned to the War
      Fund)...

      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84031081/1917-12-24/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      ARE YOU KNITTING YOUR ...
      The Moving Picture People Find Time between Scenes to Help 
      Red Cross in Its Big Winter Drive.

      Florence Nightingale Not Founder, as Commonly Supposed; 
      Organization Due to Efforts of Clara Barton

      Ask who founded the Red Cross and nine persons out of ten will reply 
      confidently "Florence Nightingale." ... The inspiration of a noble 
      American woman completed the work of the Red Cross society ... 
      This was Clara Barton, born the year after Miss Nightingale ...
      Today the necessity for universal skill [in knitting] is greater than in 
      those other days ... millions of boys in khaki and blue are clamoring 
      for the warm, worsted garments which the Red Cross is collecting ...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030431/1918-02-24/ed-1/seq-53/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Keeping Pershing's Army in Good Spirits
      Henry P. Davison, Chairman of the Red Cross War Council, 
      Explains the Way Our Soldiers Are Informed Truthfully 
      of Home Conditions

      If a cross section photograph could be taken to-day of 
      the activities of the American Red Cross, both at home 
      and abroad, the resultant picture would be a great 
      comfort to every woman who has a husband or brother, 
      father or son, enlisted in America’s fighting forces. 
      For it would show a scope of endeavor far greater than 
      the original function of the Red Cross, which was merely 
      to care for the wounded. The wounded still get attention, 
      all that the best doctors and nurses can give them; but 
      that is only one phase of the work that the American Red 
      Cross now symbolizes. The rest of the picture is new.
      ...
      “In this new picture, which has been enlarged to meet 
      the demands of modern warfare, the flag of the American 
      Red Cross flies over every camp and cantonment where 
      American men are being trained for battle, symbolizing 
      a protection to their morale as well as their creature 
      comforts. 
      ...
      ‘Moreover, every parcel [to POWs] is personally 
      receipted for by the prisoner, and the postcard receipt 
      sent back to the Red Cross ... The Red Cross has 
      already begun to send food and clothing to him and 
      that this service will be maintained as long as he remains 
      a prisoner of war.’
      ...
      ‘This is the message which the American Red Cross 
      has carried to Europe and which it will continue to 
      deliver there so long as there are hungry Allies to 
      be fed, homeless ones to be housed and broken 
      lives to be rebuilt.’
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88064293/1918-05-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "A great net of mercy drawn through an ocean of unspeakable pain"
      How Was the Last War Fund Spent?

      It is a fair question—and it is fairly answered in the
      detailed and itemized reports that have been published
      in the newspapers of every town and city of the land.
      You never saw it? Then ask at the nearest Red
      Cross Chapter, or write, for the Red Cross wants you
      to know where your money went.

      They say that Red Cross supplies have a way of
      coming through on time.
      Italy surely has found us not wanting in prompt
      ness when her great trial came.
      And Roumania—they said no allied nation could
      get through to help her dire need.
      But the Red Cross found a way.

      It’s not always a cheap way—“Needs must”
      costs money. But did you give that money to be
      saved—or to save lives? ...
      And of one thing you may be sure. Not one
      penny of that Hundred Million has gone for anything
      but War Relief.

      Your Red Cross needs another hundred million to
      lighten just a little of the awful load of misery “over
      there.” Your share is all that you can give—and
      then a little more.
      Will you hold up your end?
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015387/1918-05-18/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      THE BIG DRIVE FOR RED CROSS COMMENCES MONDAY
      Committees Appointed and Allotments Made In Various Wards.
      COVINGTON PARADE SATURDAY EVENING
      St. Tammany Parish Is Expected To Again Go Over The Top.

      Parish Chairman Poitevent has appointed chairmen in the different wards 
      to take charge of the Second Red Cross Drive, which starts Monday, May 20, 
      and these chairmen have appointed their local committeemen. The allotments 
      have been made for the different wards, and the total parish allotment of 
      $15,000 has been as equitably distributed as possible...

      Covington—E. G. Davis, E. J. Domergue, S. C. Bull, H. A. Mackie, ...
      John L. Haller, ward chairman, Third Ward, ...
      Each ward will provide for its own demonstrations and parades. 
      The Covington parade will take place at 5 o'clock to-day and will be 
      participated in by the Red Cross, the schools and St. Paul's College and 
      St. Scholastica's Academy...

      Capt. Herbert Smith, who spent nine months in the trenches at the front 
      ... spoke for the Red Cross at Slidell and Abita Springs, and Wednesday at 
      Covington. He related experiences of war conditions and the vital aid the 
      Red Cross provides to soldiers in the trenches...

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn87065462/1918-12-12/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "NEW Red Cross Call" 
      "Roll of Member"

      Every Patriotic Citizen Urged to Help in Solution
      of Problems of Peace by Joining; America's Greatest Institution.

      WASHINGTON, D. C. Henry P. Davison, Chairman of the 
      War Council of the Red Cross, has issued to the 3,884 
      chapters and 22,000,000 members of the American Red Cross
      the following statement outlining the future policy of the American
      Red Cross:

      "The Roll Call of the nation is thus to be called at Christmas 
      time, that through enrollment in their Red Cross the American
      people may send a message to our soldiers still overseas and to 
      the peoples of the world that we are not merely content with 
      seeing our privates united with our allies in victory, but that our 
      abiding purpose is that the love, the sympathy and the intelligence 
      of all America shall be re-dedicated to the permanent service of
      mankind."
      —H. P. DAVISON

        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn88056166/1918-05-10/ed-1/seq-6/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      "A Great Net of Mercy drawn through an Ocean of Unspeakable Pain"
      —American Red Cross

      The Call From No Man's Land

      The Spending of Your Hundred Million Dollars
      Busiest Budget in All the World Is a Red Cross War Fund
      —Every Dollar Spent Alleviates Misery.

      Last summer the public subscribed a hundred million dollars 
      to the Red Cross. ... It’s amazing that it [the Red Cross] has done 
      so much with so little money.

      ... The American Red Cross’ enormous job is to do whatever 
      it can to alleviate [suffering]—not after the war, not after governments 
      have deliberated and resolved; but right now, on the spot. ...

      [Article describes in detail how millions of dollars in Red Cross 
      funds were spent to assist refugees, to build hospitals, to provide 
      food, shelter, medical services and canteen services for soldiers 
      in France, Italy, and elsewhere, alleviating misery on an 
      unprecedented scale...]

      Every dollar it spends means misery alleviated. Its work 
      is building abroad for the United States the best good will in 
      this world. Whatever else the war may produce, we shall 
      be proud of our Red Cross.

      —From the Cottonwood chronicle (Idaho), May 10, 1918.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87065528/1944-04-28/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=world+war+i&amp;r=-0.642,-0.015,2.284,1.409,0</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83004278/1957-04-04/ed-1/?sp=13&amp;q=world+war+i</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86075189/1948-09-24/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=world+war+i</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036106/1947-10-02/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=world+war+i</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85053044/1945-02-16/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=world+war+i</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-halloween/selected-articles</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014760/1861-10-31/ed-1/?sp=3&amp;q=Halloween+Hallow+Hallowmas&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.027,0.364,0.688,0.849,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          LOCAL NEWS.
          To AdTMTtlMM.
          Nearly m thousand eopiea uf tho Jlrjwb
          Mean are olroulated among tha floating pnputa
          tton every day.besides thelarge number served
          to regular subscribers. Advertisers will late
          note accordingly.

          Alt Hallow Ke.
          To-night Is it!q IUItoto Tee, or Hallow n'en,
          as being tlie vigil or ove uf Ml Hallow Day
          Tbe Jlomlsh Church designed this day to bo
          held In boner nf all those taints who had not
          particular days appointed for them, but Ittloes
          not appear that All nallowD,iy,or Its eye, oro
          ever marked by very particular observance
          In the Cathollo ohurchj novertholess. there
          Is Boarcoly any tlmo more distinguished by the
          common feoplo of many portions uf the Brlltsh
          Kinging of bells was one of tho modes of
          celebrating Hallowmas m tngiana in umos piui.
          It whs a Itoman Oathn.lo practice, being da
          signed In aomo way to flvr the souls or de
          parted Christians. For this reason, Queon
          Elizabeth prohibited It. It was also A custom,
          a few centuries ago, to have a cake oaken on
          this eve for overy member of the family, ns a
          tout mass cake or soul cake. It was oomposod
          of natmeal, and seoded; and pasties and fur
          mety were Incidental to tho samo evening. In
          families of good condition, a quantity were
          hfllrnn unit ant nn on a board, liko tbe shew-
          bread In old pictures In tbo Bible, to bo given
          tp visiters, or distributed among the poor.
          Thero was a rhymo for tbe ocoaslon A soul
          cako a soul cake 1 Havo mercy on uu uuns
          Man snult lor a soul-oaks I" Poonle went from
          parish to parish o soulinj. as they oalled II,
          that Is, begklng In a kind of ohant for soul
          oakes, or anything to in ike them merry on this
          eve.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84027008/1866-10-31/ed-1/?sp=4&amp;q=HALLOWE%27EN+Hallowe%27en&amp;st=text&amp;r=0.076,0.069,0.534,0.659,0</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          HALLOWE'EN*
          SOPHY LA??GHAM'S DIARY.

          MALDON HALL, October 27, 1846.—
          We have been a week here to-day,
          and I have never once opened my
          diary. This year is fast waxing to
          its close, and I feel I must write
          retrospectively, recording the events
          omitted, as best I can, from memory.

          Our parting from mamma was a
          sad one; we had never left her be?
          fore. Still, Miss Langham's invita?
          tion came so unexpectedly, and with
          the mention of All Hallow E'en
          drawing near, that we decided to
          accept. Perhaps in this ancient
          Hall we shall witness old customs
          or legends of the season. The old
          tree-lined drive and the chill autumn
          twilight gave me a strange sense
          of awe when we arrived here...

          I can hardly believe Hallowe'en
          is so close at hand. There is a hush
          throughout these grand halls, as if
          the house itself remembered ages
          past of our family. We shall see
          what the vigil of All Hallows brings.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82003389/1868-11-11/ed-1/?sp=2&amp;q=Hallow+ALL+HALLOW+EVE</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          THE ELECTION--Tr E REIULT As FAR As
          HEARD FROM-ALL HALLOW RYE--AL
          SAINTS DAY.

          ITurning from the thread-bare subject of
          politics, which have been discussed with
          animation for several months past, I will
          say a few words about

          ALL HALLOW EVE.
          The last of October, the eve of All Saints
          Day, has been for ages a time of festivities,
          peculiar costumes and ceremonies, in the
          old countries, but of these there are few
          traces in our country. It is a season when
          fairies and wood-land elves come out in
          force, play pranks on passers by, dance
          merrily on the bill sides, and perform fa
          vors for those who have the good fortune
          to meet with them and fall into their good
          graces ...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn94052989/1891-10-31/ed-1/?sp=8&amp;q=spirits+All+children+Hallow+eve</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          A NIGHT OF MYSTERY.
          Some Curious Facts Concerning All Hallow Even.

          The Night When Maidens Try to Find Out
          Who Will Wed Them— A Curious Cir-
          cumstance— Tricks Played.

          [Written for The Morning Call]

          All boys and girls know that October 31st
          is "All Hallow Even," though most of them
          corrupt its name to "Holly Eve." They
          know that it is a night of mirth and mys-
          tery specially devoted to mischief, fun, in-
          cantations, divination charms and spells,
          but very few of them or their elders under-
          stand its real significance or can tell whence
          it derives its name.

          It is many centuries since the Roman
          Church, finding it impossible, from the
          great and constantly increasing multitude of
          the saints, to set apart a separate day for
          each one, decreed that November 1st should
          thenceforward be kept as a day in honor of
          all the saints, and that it should be known
          as All Hallow Mas, or All Saints' day, and
          that the night of October 31st, immediately
          preceding it, should thereafter be kept as a
          vigil and known as All Hallow eve, these
          occasions being still observed in the Cath-
          olic, Episcopal and Lutheran churches...
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83025121/1895-11-29/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=celebrations+Halloween+celebrated</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          TIS FAIRIES NIGHT.
          ALL Halloween, when to your
          sight may be, I ween,
          Some curious facts concerning
          All Hallow Even.

          From its first origination Hallow eve has
          been invested with a peculiarly mystic
          character. It is an almost universal super
          stition that supernatural influences then
          have unusual power—that devils, witches
          and fairies roam free; that all spirits are
          loosed to roam through space, and that the
          spiritual element in humanity can be
          detached to read its own future or reveal
          the fortunes of others.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1899-10-29/ed-1/?sp=23&amp;q=Halloween+soul+souls</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      On Tuesday, October 31, is Halloween, Halloween. The very mention of
      Halloween calls up visions of ghosts and witches and all kinds of uncanny
      things. It is the one night in the year when even the uninitiated, if they are
      brave enough, may converse with spooks and hobgoblins, and may also, if they
      try hard enough, send the immaterial part of their being prancing through
      space on all kinds of errands. But the grand object of all the mystic rites
      peculiar to Halloween is to find out who one’s future spouse will be—that being
      a very important question with those who have never had one.

      Another way that does not require so much courage is to write the alphabet
      on twenty-six little slips of paper, one letter on each slip, and then turn them
      face down in a basin of water. This done, go to bed backward and in silence.
      Next morning some of the letters in the basin will be found face up and the name
      thus revealed will give the desired information.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052116/1905-10-26/ed-1/?sp=7&amp;q=HALLOWEEN+Halloween+Hallow+H</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Halloween was the eve of Hallowmas, and on that night 
      ghosts, goblins, witches and fairies were believed 
      to be turned loose upon the Earth. 
      It also was the favorite time for testing fortune, 
      for the veil that hid the future hung so waveringly 
      that one, by proper signs and devices, might get 
      a peep behind it.

      In many tests of fortune the apple plays a part, 
      big with prophecy of things to come. 
      Eat one before a mirror in a darkened room on Halloween 
      and your future spouse will look over your shoulder; 
      throw the peel over your left shoulder and it will 
      form the initial of the one you are to marry.
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1907-11-03/ed-1/?sp=32&amp;q=Hallowe%27en+celebrated+celebration</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      OUR SPECIAL FEATURE PAGE

      No holiday on the calendar depends more for its charm upon tradition 
      and the customs handed down from generation to generation than does 
      that fateful night of mirth and mystery—Hallowe'en. ... Hallowe'en not 
      only retains its time-honored significance and long-established ritual but 
      finds its chief attraction in these reminders of bygone periods.

      The festival of the night of October 31 has a number of different 
      designations, though none are so commonly used as Hallowe'en. ... 
      From time out of mind this has been heralded as a night when witches, 
      devils and other mischief-making beings go abroad on their baneful 
      midnight errands. By a strange coincidence, however, this same night 
      is supposed to be devoted by the fairies to a grand anniversary celebration.
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042462/1909-10-24/ed-1/?sp=38&amp;q=Hallowe%27en+HALLOWE%27EN+celebrations+celebration</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Now approaches the witch's hour, when, hand in hand with jack-o'-lantern, 
      she is prepared to scamper across the curtain for an interlude of frolic.
      The black cat is with us again, and the bat, and the owl. The
      cauldron bubbles, the chestnuts burn upon the hearth, the Hallowe'en cake
      gives up its ghostly prophecy of wealth, matrimony or a life of single
      blessedness...

      Hallowe'en 'nativities are always very popular with girls, and they
      are possible for every one, for the celebration of the night has one great
      advantage in the fact that its mystic rites and ceremonies can be just as
      well and happily performed by three or four persons as by a large number.
      Naturally the sort of Hallowe'en entertainment which is arranged for a small
      gathering is not satisfactory for a large one...
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045211/1914-10-31/ed-1/?sp=12&amp;q=HALLOWEEN+Halloween+HALLOWE%27EN+Hallowe%27en+celebrate+celebration</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      FAIRIES' HALLOWEEN PARTY

      The Halloween fairies were giving a party. There was the pumpkin fairy, 
      in shimmering shining yellow; the apple fairy in russet and green; 
      the nut fairies in golden browns, and many others into the bargain. 
      They were giving their party in the hollow of a great big oak tree. 
      Friendly fireflies had offered to furnish the illumination, and so many of them 
      came that there wasn’t the least bit of danger that their lights would all go out 
      at the same time...

      The Origin of Halloween

      The only mysterious festival left to prosaic Americans is Halloween. 
      Its origin is plainly Pagan, although the romantic element has come to us 
      from England, Ireland and Scotland. Around the 1st of November the Druids 
      were supposed to hold their worship of the sun god, thanking him for the harvest. 
      Huge sacrificial fires were lighted in his honor, which influence can still be seen 
      in the “bonfire night” in Ireland. This is the night when witches, elves, 
      and evil spirits walk abroad, souring the cream, tying cats’ tails together, 
      and performing pranks usually attributed to small boys.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1938-10-29/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=halloween</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Hostelries Keeping Program Secret
      Until Opening

      By THE NIGHT CLUB EDITOR
      If Washington case society doesn’t celebrate Halloween this year 
      it won’t be the hotels’ fault. Every hostelry in town is making 
      fevered preparations for the festival and all of ’em are trying 
      to keep it a secret—until the opening. 
      Sande Williams and his orchestra now playing in the Shar-Zad Room 
      at the Carlton Hotel are holding rehearsals behind locked doors. 
      Those weird sounds can mean only one thing. The witches and goblins 
      are tuning up.

      The Shoreham will make a special occasion of this autumn festival 
      partly because it is Halloween and partly because it marks the eighth 
      anniversary of the hostelry’s opening. 
      Nadine Petrey, Washington’s own Halloween queen, will visit 
      the Blue Room. Nadine, a pretty lass of 17, will be accompanied 
      by her ladies-in-waiting, her jesters, and—of course—her king.
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1912-10-27/ed-1/?sp=16&amp;q=halloween</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Boys and girls were afforded an opportunity to learn 
      the initials of the person most closely connected 
      with their futures in one Halloween frolic. A dish of water 
      darkened with sepia, and another of clear, were produced, as well 
      as sticks of sealing wax—one half white, the other black. 
      To discover the first (Christian) name, a youth or maiden 
      lighted the white wax, holding it over the dish of dark water 
      until a drop fell, then dipped it out on a spoon. Sometimes 
      the initial was clearly indicated; in others, there was a faint 
      suggestion, or no shape at all, interpreted as either a 
      doubt of romance or a fate too distant to be revealed.

      In another pretty charm, a small tub of water was used. 
      The names of unmarried men were written on squares of paper, 
      twisted to resist the water, then placed afloat. At the same time, 
      a candle end—glued to a chip—was lit and set adrift. If the 
      flame first ignited one of the papers, that indicated the youth 
      would be the lassie’s next suitor, for he "had first felt the fire 
      of love.” 
      </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1935-10-30/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=halloween</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      Halloween is just around the corner, which means extra
      special gayety in the after-dark spots. Every spot that
      caters to whoopee-makers is making an extra effort for a
      gala evening. Entertainment ranges from the usual
      noisemakers to the importation of headline acts from
      New York—so collect your energy, shekels, and fine duds
      and go out and have yourself a time.

      Tomorrow night is the first anniversary of the opening
      of the Maryland Winter Gardens, and this event, along
      with Halloween, ought to make, and probably will, an
      evening full of entertainment. Brian McDonald, master
      of ceremonies, is back after an eight months absence, and
      it looks like plenty of war-whooping out on the old
      Marlboro Pike.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045462/1912-10-27/ed-1/?sp=48&amp;q=halloween</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      WITCH-LIKE ACTIONS
      Would Have Meant
      Sure Death in the Old Days

      Even in our own country the hallucinations that certain persons were
      endowed with the power of conversing with evil spirits ran riot in the
      little colony of Salem in 1692. At that time persons were put to death
      or imprisoned not only for being witches, but for asserting their unbelief
      in witchcraft. Today the people of the little Massachusetts town still point
      out “Witches’ Hill,” where several innocent women were executed. The
      madness of the colony spared neither the weak-minded Indian maiden
      Tituba, who was seen practicing ceremonies of her own heathen religion,
      nor such exemplary women as Sarah Cloyce and Rebecca Nurse.

      Cats Are Always Connected
      With Halloween Celebrations

      Cats are always singled out as closely connected with witches and
      with Halloween. Long before any real knowledge of the animal’s habits
      existed, cats were believed to be endowed with magic powers, and it was
      thought “bad luck” to kill one, since the creature’s spirit might seek
      vengeance. Hence the black cat, companion of witches and a symbol
      of mystic powers, remains a staple element in modern Halloween
      festivities, to give the night’s frolic that eerie effect of the unknown.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84026749/1935-10-30/ed-1/?sp=20&amp;q=halloween</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
      ALL READY FOR HALLOWEEN
      Cotton Club Is Far From Closed
      As Surprises Are Planned
      For Tomorrow Night

      By THE NIGHT CLUB EDITOR

      Halloween is just around the corner, which means extra
      special gayety in the after-dark spots. This festival really
      inaugurates the fall and winter season in the hotels and
      supper clubs, and finds Washington prepared to step out
      in carnival mood. Every spot that caters to whoopee-makers
      is making an extra effort for a gala evening.
      </text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
